Contact

+56 9 51218631 (Home) pviojo@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/pviojo (LinkedIn) pablo-viojo.com (Personal)

Top Skills

Company Set-up
UX Research
High Availability (HA)

Languages

English (Professional Working)
Italian (Full Professional)
Spanish (Native or Bilingual)
Portuguese (Elementary)

Pablo Viojo

Business, Technology and Operations Chile

Summary

Tech Leader at Grin

Former COO and CTO at Groupon Latam.

Cofounder at Latam Builders.

Former COO and cofounder at babytuto.com

Former COO, CTO and cofounder at Groupon Latam.

Experience in Operations Management focused on the design and control of processes in the e-commerce industry developing and implementing different KPIs. Having managed Groupon operations in Chile, Argentina, Uruguay, Perú, Colombia, Panamá, Mexico and Puerto Rico and cofounded my own e-commerce company (babytuto.com) I have a strong knowledge of the Latinoamerica e-commerce reality.

Beside this, I'm a software developer. primarily focused on UI/UX, architecture and development. Advanced skills on Python, Javascript, React, PHP, MySQL, PostgreSQL, etc.

Skills:

Operations Management, Project Management, Logisitic, IT Consultancy.

Software engineering, Python, Javascript, React, PHP, MySQL et al, AWS, GCP, User Experience

Implementation and operation of Highly available systems

Experience

Grin Scooters

Tech Leader

November 2021 - Present (1 year 9 months)

Santiago, Santiago Metropolitan Region, Chile

Qoopit App

Cofounder

March 2021 - Present (2 years 5 months)

Groupon Latam

13 years 5 months

Cofounder at Groupon Latam

March 2010 - Present (13 years 5 months)

COO and CTO

2017 - February 2021 (4 years)

Santiago Province, Chile

Latam Builders

Cofounder

August 2015 - Present (8 years)

Babytuto

COO

July 2013 - August 2015 (2 years 2 months)

http://www.babytuto.com

Groupon

2 years 10 months

Head of Services Latam

February 2013 - March 2013 (2 months)

Santiago, Chile

COO Latam

August 2012 - January 2013 (6 months)

Santiago

COO, CTO, Co-Founder Latam

June 2010 - July 2012 (2 years 2 months)

Chile

Undisclosed

Code Artist

February 2009 - June 2010 (1 year 5 months)

Needish

Code Artist

June 2008 - June 2010 (2 years 1 month)

Freelance

Cakephp developer

April 2005 - June 2010 (5 years 3 months)

CakePHP is a web application framework written in PHP, modeled after the concepts of Ruby on Rails. (MVC, ActiveRecord)

Accenture

UI Creator (RIA, J2EE project) & UI Team Manager June 2007 - June 2008 (1 year 1 month)

Working as a UI Team Manager & Creator for a modern web application, for one of the biggest IT providers in Chile

Needish

Cakephp and UI developer May 2007 - July 2007 (3 months)

Design and development

©Soho

UI Developer and Architect, J2EE Developer November 2005 - May 2007 (1 year 7 months)

J2EE financial application development. Advanced Javascript and Ajax, Flex and other related technologies. Consultancy on UI architecure, performance and security areas.

Undisclosed

8 months

Project Manager

September 2005 - November 2005 (3 months)

Project Management for Civil Engineering/Construction Projects

Developer

April 2005 - November 2005 (8 months)

Internet and Desktop development using ASP, .NET, MSSQL Server.

Education

Universidad de la República (Uruguay) Civil Engineering, Project Management · (2000 - 2005)